Milind Ahiwale

Prabuddha Vihar, Phaltan, Satara (Maharashtra) - 415523 **Tel.:** +91-9403058880, **E-mail:** ahiwale.milind@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/milind-ahiwale/

PROFILE

Strong research and financial analytical abilities, good team-player, self-motivated, and hardworking Finance graduate, able to maintain focus in demanding work environments. Quick to understand new ideas and concepts and always find a way to effectively use the integration of acquired knowledge and skill to complete complex tasks. Out spoken and appreciates active discussions.

Work Experience

Research Intern at Reserve Bank of India (RBI)

Jan 2019 – June 2019

Financial Stability Unit

- Actively engaged in data analytics to pick up potential vulnerabilities and triggers to systemic risks in Indian Banking under supervision of Director General Manager.
- Involving in projects of Foreign National Banks (FNB), Privet sector banks (PVB), Public Sector Banks (PSB), Non-Banking Financial Corporations (NBFC), Mutual funds, Fixed Maturity Plans (FMP).
- Worked on a research of RBI's proposal of converting FNB's branches working in India into wholly owned subsidiaries (WOS).
- Involved in drafting inputs to the Financial Stability Report for the coming June 2019 publication.
- Performed prediction scenario analysis like stress testing, sensitivity analysis using excel.

Responsibilities:

- Conduct of macro-prudential surveillance of the financial system on an ongoing basis
- Preparation of financial stability reports
- Development of a database of key variables which could impact financial stability, in co-ordination with the supervisory wings of the Reserve Bank
- Development of a time series of a core set of financial indicators
- Conduct of systemic stress tests to assess resilience and
- Development of models for assessing financial stability

International Student Ambassador

June 2017 –Sept 2017

University of Southampton (United Kingdom)

- Provided courses information to the students and parents on University open days.
- Assisted International office on their administrative work.
- Attended compulsory training events, designed to provide an introduction to working with young people, child protection and presentation skills.

Business Analyst Intern

Aug 2015 – Sept 2016

CentPro Engineering Privet Limited (Pune)

- Provided alternatives/recommendations to reduce product costs and improve financial performance of exports for Egypt and Vietnam.
- Analysed company's balance-sheet and worked closely with managers on development projects.

Education

University of Southampton (United Kingdom)

Sep 2016 – Dec 2017

Master of Science in Finance

Dissertation: Herding in Bitcoin Market

- Developed strong analytical skills and demonstrated a high level of accuracy in assessed assignments and written reports. Reports included the identification of potential market risks and opportunities for firms and the application of capital budgeting techniques.
- Researched and analyzed financial and economic data and identified trends using software's such as E-views and SPSS.
- Coordinated tasks in group projects and arranged responsibilities.
- Delivered projects in a professional manner and within tight deadlines; both individually and part of a team. Projects included the financial valuation of firms, the analysis of their historical financial performance based on financial statements and ratios, the development of financial models and the recommendation of key decisions to improve firms' strategic outcomes.

Modules: Advanced Corporate Finance, Advanced Time Series Management, Behavioural Finance, International Finance, Quantitative Finance, Stock Market Analysis, Portfolio Management and Traded Derivatives.

Fergusson College (University of Pune)

Jun 2013 – Apr 2016

Bachelor in Economics

Modules: Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Banking, International Economics, Political Science, Sociology.

Achievement: Foreign Education Scholarship 2016-17 by State Government of Maharashtra, India

<u>IT Skills:</u> Proficient in MS office suite, including; Excel (VBA, Pivot Table, vlookup), Word, PowerPoint, Outlook. Power BI

Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi

_